BRIAN CERNEY

brianecerney@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Focused, flexible developer with 4+ years' experience delivering, enhancing, and automating enterprise-scale software in an Agile environment. AWS Certified Solutions Architect, with SaaS, Cloud, DevOps, and CI/CD experience across multiple platforms and stacks. Team-oriented, T-shaped, and ready to collaborate across the SDLC. Former teacher committed to continuing education, with a knack for learning new skills guickly.

TECHNICAL TOOLS

Proficient | Python, Flask, Django, Pytest, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, REST APIs, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Kustomize, Terraform, Terragrunt, Ansible, Linux, Bash, Git, GitLab, Jenkins, DataDog, VS Code
 Exposure | Java, Spring, JUnit, Celery, TypeScript, Angular, OpenStack, Heroku, Argo CD, Splunk, IntelliJ

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2021 – Present

Platform Engineering, Immuta, Columbus, OH

- Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, TypeScript, Angular, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS, Argo CD, DataDog
- Developed asynchronous in-cluster Kubernetes agent for multi-region provisioning of SaaS deployments
- Integrated Immuta's SaaS platform with Snowflake's Partner Connect program for one-click trial provisioning

DevOps Engineer

April 2020 – Jan 2021

Nimbis Services, Columbus, OH

- Python, Django, Celery, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, AWS, Terraform, Ansible, Packer, Linux, Windows, GitLab
- Full stack development of SaaS platforms providing self-service microelectronics design environments
- Successfully upgraded multiple apps from Django 1.1/Python 2.7 to Django 2.2/Python 3

Associate Consultant

Feb 2019 - April 2020

Workstate, Columbus, OH

DevOps Engineer, Cloud Services, CAS

July 2019 - April 2020

- Python, Pytest, Docker, Terraform, Ansible, OpenStack, AWS, Linux, Bash, GitLab CI/CD, Prometheus
- Converted OpenStack cloud provisioning CLI codebase from Bash & Ansible to Python using OpenStack SDK,
 resulting in 20% faster resource provisioning, 30% faster build times, and a 50% increase in unit test coverage
- Developed secure VM image CI/CD pipeline using Python and Gitlab, reducing OS vulnerabilities by 30%

Software Engineer, Solution Delivery, CAS

Feb 2019 - July 2019

- Java, Scala, Spark, Groovy, Hadoop, HDFS, Cascading, JavaScript, Docker, OpenStack, Linux, Jenkins, Gerrit
- Implemented addition of USPAT database (~10M records) to ETL pipeline supporting CAS's PatentPak product

Software Engineer

May 2017 - Feb 2019

Auto Finance IT, JPMorgan Chase & Co., Columbus, OH

- Java, Spring Framework, SOAP/REST, IBM MQ, JMS, JUnit, RHEL7, Tomcat 7, Bitbucket, Jenkins, PCF, Splunk
- Developed multiple Java/Spring microservices with REST/MQ APIs to enhance auto loan application workflows

PROJECTS

<u>Modded.Me</u> | Collection of lifestyle gamification web apps built using Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Celery, Redis, Bootstrap, Sphinx, Docker Compose, Gitlab CI/CD, and AWS (EC2, EBS, S3, SSM, EIP, Route 53) <u>gtRPG</u> | Guitar practice web app built using Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Jinja2, and Heroku

EDUCATION

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

September 2020

Tech Elevator Coding Bootcamp

Columbus, OH 2017

Java Web Development

California State University, Chico

Chico, CA 2012

B.A. in Music Industry and Technology (Audio Engineering)

B.A. in Comparative Religion

REFERENCES

Available upon request